COURTNEY VALENTINE SPIVEY

Artist and Programmer



PERSONAL PROFILE

As a triple major hoping to combine my passion for creativity and my knowledge of computer science, I am an organized student with a well-rounded education. I have a mixture of computer science, management & business, and art background. In addition to my work experience and academics, I am active in ACM SIGGRAPH, SWE and the NOVA fellowship.

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

- Computer Graphics
- Front End Development
- Academic Research
- React Native & Node.js
- Graphic Design

ACADEMIC SCHOLARSHIPS & HONORS

- International Saltire Scholarship 2020
- Recipient of Benjamin A. Gilman International Scholarship (2018)
- Recipient of Rotary Scholarship (2019)
- Dean's Honor Roll (2017)
- Published and Awarded artworks at the Gussman Exhibition, Stylus Magazine, and CSGC

EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

- ACM Siggraph (Former VP)
- ABC (Former VP)
- NOVA Fellowship (Lead | Org)
- The Colligiant Newspaper (Writer)
- Marching band, Wind Ensemble, and Symphonic Orchestra (Member)
- Society of Women Engineers (Member)

CONTACT

Mobile: +918 284 7012 Email: cvs393@utulsa.edu

Behance: behance.net/courtney-spivey

Published articles:

tucollegian.org/author/courtney-spivey/

CAREER EXPERIENCE

ANIMATION INSTRUCTOR

GoodLife Media Tulsa | May 2020 - September 2020

- Worked as a in class studio instructor for animation
- Taught students between the grades of 4th to 12th grade on a variety of animation techniques and created a full scale project during the more intensive summer training camp.

FREELANCE FRONT-END WEB DEVELOPER

The University of Tulsa Drilling Research Projects / May 2020 - September 2020

- Remade the complete look and feel of the TUDRP website, using Bootstrap 4, JavaScript, CSS/HTML and other design methods.
- Re-branded TUDRP with a cohesive theme, style, academic aesthetic that will be used after the completion of the website
- Used GitHub to make sure all edits after me are easily synchronized with the inital website, and configured the backend to work seamlessly with the repository.

GRAPHIC DESIGN INTERNSHIP

3rd Floor Design | August 2019 - Present

- Work as a competitive designer for non-profit organizations
- Out of 13 assignments, my work was selected as the final advertisement/logo for 9 clients. Those include works for Little Blue House, John Hope Franklin, OKAC, Booker T. Washington, Mizel, Recycling Co, The Ronald Macdonald House Foundation, and Will Rogers High School.

FULL-TIME WEB DEVELOPER

TU Housing (Canelink), Tulsa, Oklahoma | January 2019 - October 2019

- Reworked back-end supporting code on website to speed up load time
- Wrote methods to handle freshmen orientation assignments during StartTU week
- Self-taught Databases & Networks to understand back-end development, then contributed to code repository by completing tasks assigned in Agile environment

ACADEMIC BACKGROUND

The University of Abertay, Dundee - UK | 4.0 GPA | September - September 2021

Professional Masters in Game Development, Design and Production

The University of Tulsa | 3.5 GPA | August 2016 - May 2020

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science with Emphasis on Gaming Simulation and Development Bachelor of Science in Applied Mathematics

Bachelor of Science in Applied Mathematics
Bachelor of Arts In Art With Emphasis in Graphic Design
Minor in Art History

Tuscia University, Viterbo, Italy | 4.0 GPA | June - August 2018

Summer Abroad

Coursework in Intro to Italian, Italian Renaissance Arts, Sociology of Food

COURTNEY VALENTINE SPIVEY

Artist and Programmer



ART AWARDS

- (2017) Artwork accepted into Gussman Exhibit, Artwork sold
- (2018) Photography artwork accepted into Stylus magazine
- (2018) Stylus Editor
- (2019) Participating in TURC research with Professor Valero
- (2019) Merit Honor Award for Digital Video Submission at the Gussman Exhibit
- (2019) Lead Senior Design Editor for Stylus Magazine
- (2019) Recipient of Rotary Scholarship
- (2020) Sarah Clark Memorial Award in Graphic Design at the Gussman Exhibit
- (2020) Published the 19th issue of Stylus Magazine

SKILLS

- Game Programming
- Game Design
- Software Development
- Drawing
- Creative Writing
- Academic Research
- Music Composition
- Financial Analysis
- Video Editing
- 3D Modeling
- Photo Editing
- Animation
- Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, Indesign
- Procreate
- Microsoft Visual Studios
- UX/UI Design
- Material Design

CONTINUED CAREER EXPERIENCE

GAME DESIGN, PYTHON, JAVA, ACT ONLINE INSTRUCTOR

Varsity Tutors | August 2020 - Present

- Worked with students across the globe on coding, game design, java and other projects.
- One on one training for students that are academically struggling. ${\tt SENIOR}$ ${\tt DESIGN}$ ${\tt EDITOR}$

Stylus Magazine | August 2018 - Present

- In charge of all aspects of the Stylus Magazine production process as Lead Designer
- Built a cyberpunk themed website from scratch using CSS, HTML, & Javascript
- Optimized work-load in Adobe Indesign by creating up complete book template

ACADEMIC RESEARCHER

Tulsa Undergraduate Research Challenge | Januarry 2019 - November 2019

- As a multidisciplinary student, combined fields of interest to research the possibility of Artificial General Intelligence shown in the popular video game: Detroit, Become Human.
- Attended the ICCC Conference and learned about current day limitations on AI